Guide to the American Association of Advertising Agencies Records, 1918-1998
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Vertical Files Series, 1939-1993, bulk 1958-1983, (38 boxes)
  - Federal Trade Commission (FTC)
    - Modern Advertising Practices
      - Testimony, 1971
        - Galdston, Richard (Box VF29)
        - Gavitt, Frank (Box VF29)
        - Gilbert, Frederick (Box VF29)
        - Gray, Elisha (Box VF29)
        - Green, Federick (Box VF29)
        - Greyser, Stephen (Box VF29)
        - Haggerty, Edward (Box VF29)
        - Hardin, David K. (Box VF29)
        - Heiskell, Andrew (Box VF29)
        - Helitzer, Melvin (Box VF29)
        - Horner, Vivian (Box VF29)
        - Kelly, Stephen (Box VF29)
        - Kendall, Donald (Box VF29)
        - Kirkpatrick, Miles (Box VF29)
        - Krugman, Herbert (Box VF29)
        - Lehmann, Donald R. (Box VF29)
        - Light, Larry (Box VF29)
        - Loevinger, Lee (Box VF29)
        - Maneloveg, Herbert (Box VF29)
        - Mayans, Frank (Box VF29)
        - Miller, Donald (Box VF29)
      - Testimony (continued) (Box VF30)
        - Morrison, Bruce (Box VF30)
        - Neff, Jeanette (Box VF30)
        - Overholser, Charles (Box VF30)
        - O'Toole, John (Box VF30)
        - Perlmutter, Milton (Box VF30)
        - Reyes, Domingo (Box VF30)
        - Sarson, Evelyn (Box VF30)
        - Schwartz, Phillip (Box VF30)
        - Seaman, Alfred J. (Box VF30)
        - Sharp, William (Box VF30)
        - Shepherd, William (Box VF30)
        - Skinner, Lloyd E. (Box VF30)
        - Tannenbeum, Stanley (Box VF30)
        - Television Bureau of Advertising (Box VF30)
        - Thiele, Edward (Box VF30)
        - Thurm, Samuel (Box VF30)
        - Tibbetts, Hubert (Box VF30)
        - Vladimir, Andrew (Box VF30)
        - Wackman, Daniel B. (Box VF30)
        - Ward, Scott (Box VF30)
        - Webber, Gordon (Box VF30)
        - Weil, Gilbert (Box VF30)
      - Transcripts, 1971 Oct-Nov., (1-5 of 11 folders) (Box VF30)
      - Transcripts, 1971 Oct-Nov. (continued), (6-11 of 11 folders) (Box VF31)
    - Trade Regulation Rule
      - General, 1970-1983
        - Act (Box VF31)
        - Advertising techniques (Box VF31)
        - Air conditioning (Box VF32)
        - Antacid labeling (Box VF32)
        - Care labeling rule (Box VF32)
        - Codification (Box VF32)
        - Drugs-OTC, (6 folders) (Box VF32)
        - Food, (1 of 8 folders) (Box VF32)
        - Food (continued), (2-8 of 8 folders) (Box VF33)
        - Funeral service industry (Box VF33)
        - Health spas (Box VF34)
        - Hearing aids (Box VF34)
        - Mail order merchandise (Box VF34)
        - Mobile homes (Box VF34)
        - Negative option plans (Box VF34)
        - Opthalmic goods and services (Box VF34)
        - Preservation of consumer claim (Box VF34)
        - Standards and certification (Box VF34)
        - Used cars (Box VF34)
        - Vocational and home study schools (Box VF34)
  - Food and Drug Administration
    - Drugs--OTC
      - General, 1970-1981, (2 folders) (Box VF34)
      - Analgesics, 1975-1980 (Box VF34)
      - Antacids, 1972-1978 (Box VF35)
      - Anti-perspirants, 1976-1978 (Box VF35)
      - Contraceptives and vaginal products, 1975-1978 (Box VF35)
      - Cough/cold remedies, 1972-1976 (Box VF35)
      - Dentrifrices, 1975-1978 (Box VF35)
      - Ethical drugs, 1975-1978 (Box VF35)
      - Hemorrhoidal drugs, 1975-1978 (Box VF35)
      - Laxatives, 1975-1978 (Box VF35)
      - Opthalmic drugs, 1975-1979 (Box VF35)
      - Oral cavity drugs, 1975-1978 (Box VF35)
      - Sedatives, 1975-1979 (Box VF35)
      - Vitamins, 1973-1979 (Box VF35)
    - Drugs--Prescription
      - Reviews, 1971-1979 (Box VF35)
    - Labeling
      - Hexachlorophene, 1972-1977 (Box VF35)
      - Mouthwash/gargle, 1970-1971 (Box VF35)
      - Nutritional claims, 1970-1990 (Box VF35)
      - Orange juice, 1971-1972 (Box VF35)
  - Political Advertising
    - 1959-1972, (8 folders; 5 folders moved to Oversized Box VF39) (Box VF35)
    - 1973-1979, (9 folders) (Box VF36)
    - 1980-1984, (6 folders) (Box VF37)
  - Rights of Publishers to Refuse/Accept Advertising, 1927-1958 and undated (Box VF37)
  - Self-Regulation
    - NAB (National Association of Broadcasters) codes, 1939 (Box VF37)
    - NAB radio codes, 1965-1980, (2 folders) (Box VF37)
    - NAB television codes, 1952-1981, (3 folders) (Box VF38)
    - Other pamphlets, 1948, 1974 (Box VF38)
  - Large-format political advertisements, 1966-1968, (5 folders) (Box VF39)
    [Includes advertisements for the Humphrey-Muskie, Nixon-Agnew, Eugene McCarthy and Nelson Rockefeller presidential campaigns.]
- Audiovisual Materials Series, 1977-1978 (RESTRICTED), (5 boxes)
  Restrictions on access: Originals closed to patron use. Use copies are currently available for some items. Technical Services staff may need to produce use copies before contents can be accessed. Please contact Research Services staff before coming to use the collection.
  - OR1. Conversation about Advertising with Bill Bernbach, 1977. Format: 2 in. video. Use copy available in collection. (Box AV1)
  - OR2. Conversations with David Ogilvy, 1977. Format: 2 in. video. (Box AV2)
  - OR3. Conversations with William Bernbach, 1977. Format: 2 in. video. Use copy available in collection. (Box AV3)
  - OR4. Gallup Interview, 1978. Format: 2 in. video. (Box AV4)
  - OR5. David Ogilvy interview, quad dub film transfer, 1977. Format: 2 in. video. (Box AV5)
  - OR6. David Ogilvy interview, tape 2, 1977. Format: 2 in. video. (Box AV5)
  - OR7. David Ogilvy interview, tape 3, 1977. Format: 2 in. video. (Box AV5)
  - Video additions (Box AV6)
    - OR8. Advertising Council: Finding Solutions. Undated. trt: 24:35. Format: Umatic. (Box AV6)
    - OR9. Many Faces of Marketing: Part 2, Florence Skelly. Dub 1984 June. trt: 45:00. Format: Umatic. (Box AV6)
    - OR10. More Creative the Ad, the Harder It Works. Part 1. Undated. trt: 35:00. Format: Umatic. (Box AV6)
    - OR11. More Creative the Ad, the Harder It Works. Part 2. Undated. trt: 25:00. Format: Umatic. (Box AV6)
    - OR12. More Creative the Ad, the Harder It Works. Part 3. Undated. trt: 25:00. Format: Umatic. (Box AV6)
    - OR13. More Creative the Ad, the Harder It Works. Part 4. Undated. trt: 25:00. Format: Umatic. (Box AV6)
    - OR14. Self-Regulation. 1984 Apr. trt: unknown. Format: Umatic. (Box AV6)
  - Production masters for OR1, OR3. Created: 2007. Format: Betacam. (Box AV7)
Chronological Listing of Articles Collected under the Heading Advertising in Times of Recession/War
1939. Chevalier, Col. Willard T. Why Advertise During a Seller's Market? Industrial Marketing, Dec.
1939. Peterson, Eldridge. We're Oversold! Why Keep On Advertising? Old Question Up Again. Printers' Ink, Oct. 13
1939. Peterson, Eldridge. Why Keep On Advertising When Oversold? Case Histories from World War Times. Printers' Ink, Oct. 20.
1940. Gebhart, Walter H. Proof That Business Cannot Affort to Abandon Advertising, Industrial Marketing, Oct.
1941. Baker, Melvin H. Oversold, Yet Company Begins First Consumer Copy and a 10-Year Program. Printers' Ink, Sept. 12.
1941. Erbes, P.H. Jr. This Machine-Tool Maker, Though Oversold, Pursues Fourfold Advertising Goal. Printers' Ink, July 25.
1941. Larrabee, C.B. Neglect of Good-Will While Selling is Easy ... Will Penalize Future. Printers' Ink, Feb. 21.
1941. Low, Ernest C. and Andros, E.W. New Jobs for Advertising. Printers' Ink, Sept. 12
1941. Mathy, E.L. Why Continue to Advertise When We are Sold Out? Forbes, Aug. 1.
1941. Reiss, Joseph. Industrial Advertisers Bid for Business in a Sellers' Market. Sales Management, May 1.
1941. Swan, Carroll J. Graybar, Oversold, Advertises to Guard Post-War Good-Will. Printers' Ink, Nov. 14.
Circa 1942. Unattributed. It's a Favorable Wind...Sail With It!
1942. Unattributed. There's Still Plenty to Say. Advertising Age, Mar. 2.
1942. Gibney, Raymond G. Nothing to Sell, Much to Advertise: Alcoa's '42 View. Text of newspaper campaign undertaken by the Fuller, Smith and Ross agency.
1943. Cloyes, Corrie, compiler. Advertising and Its Role in War and Peace. U.S. Department of Commerce Bureau of Foreign and Domestic Commerce publucation.
1946. AAAA Special Committee on Advertiser Relations. Comments on the Value of Advertising in Times of Shortages.
1950. Teeter, Carl. Why Advertise During Wartime Shortages. AAAA Pacific Council, Oct. 10.
1950. Unattributed. A Product is Never Oversold--It's Merely Underproduced. Printers' Ink, Aug. 18.
1950. Unattributed. Advertiser's Guide to a Sellers' Market. Printers' Ink, Sept. 8.
1950. Unattributed. Advice to Advertisers. Tide, Sept. 8.
1950. Unattributed. All Sold Out? What Can Your Ads Say? Source unknown, Dec. 1.
1950. Unattributed. Are You Oversold? 20 Reasons Why Your Advertising Should Continue. Advertising Age, Sept. 4.
1950. Unattributed. How Ads Helped Business Deal with War Perils. Advertising Age, Aug. 28.
1950. Unattributed. Minutes of Meeting on Grey Advertising Policy for Clients Faced with Shortages. Grey Matter, Aug. 30.
1951. Helbig, Raymond C. The Power of Industrial Advertising as a Tool of Defense. Remarks given at NIAA meeting, The Pentagon, Feb. 15.
1951. Hopper, Schuyler. The Power of Industrial Advertising as a Tool of Defense. Remarks given at NIAA meeting, The Pentagon, Feb. 15.
1951. Johnson, Arno. Marketing in a Defense Economy. J. Walter Thompson Company report.
1951. Lang, C.H. How Hard Must We Sell When Demand Gets Ahead of Supply? Industrial Marketing, Jan.
1951. Leland, Henry W. The Power of Industrial Advertising as a Tool of Defense. Remarks given at NIAA meeting, The Pentagon, Feb. 15.
1951. Luna, E.F. The Power of Industrial Advertising as a Tool of Defense. Remarks given at NIAA meeting, The Pentagon, Feb. 15.
1951. Reed, Russel A. The Power of Industrial Advertising as a Tool of Defense. Remarks given at NIAA meeting, The Pentagon, Feb. 15.
1951. Salisbury, Philip. 227 Reasons for Continued Selling--Even Though There's Nothing to Sell. Sales Management, Jan. 1.
1951. Simmons, H.H. The Power of Industrial Advertising as a Tool of Defense. Remarks given at NIAA meeting, The Pentagon, Feb. 15.
1951. Tofte, Arthur R, The Power of Industrial Advertising as a Tool of Defense. Remarks given at NIAA meeting, The Pentagon, Feb. 15.
1951. Unattributed. Gamble Stresses Role of Advertising in Mobilized Economy. AAAA press release, Jan. 19.
1952. Why Advertise When You're in a Sellers' Market? Sales Management, July 15.
1958. Unattributed. Advertising Has Important Role in a Recession Economy. Advertising Agency Magazine, Mar. 28.
1958. Unattributed. Advertising in Recession Periods--A New Yardstick. Printers' Ink Special Report, Aug. 29.
1958. Unattributed. How Does Advertising Affect Sales and Company Growth in Recession and Boom? Printers' Ink Special Report, Aug. 29.
1958. Unattributed. Who's Beating the Recession? Sales Management, June 6.
1960. Unattributed. How to Beat a Recession Industrial Marketing, Dec.
1961. Kaselow, Joseph. Lever Does Something About the Recession. N.Y. Herald Tribune, Mar. 30.
1961. Unattributed. The Cans and Cannots: What to Expect from Ads During an Economic Recession. Broadcasting, May 8.
1961. Unattributed. Moral: Don't Cut Ad Budgets When the Recession Knocks. Sales Management, Mar. 17.
1962. Joyce, Walter. How to Advertise Out of a Recession. Printers' Ink, Nov. 2.
1965. Ramond, Charles K. Must Advertising Communicate to Sell? Harvard Business Review, Sept.-Oct.
1970. Dougherty, Philip H. Advertising: SSC&B Marks Its 25th Year. New York Times, July 24.
1970. Unattributed. Study Shows Profits Hurt By Ad Cuts During Recessions. Southern Advertising, Dec.
Circa 1970. Unattributed. What About a Recession? A&SP Staff Roundup.
1971. Sawyer, Howard G. Sawyer: On Comparing Media; Advertising in Recessions. Industrial Marketing, Apr.
1971. Unattributed. Recession Doesn't Cool Zeal of Top 100 Spot TV Advertisers. Advertising Age, May 10.
1973. Cohan, George S. The New Role of Advertising in a Period of Shortage. Industrial Marketing, Nov.
1973. Weiss, E.B. Advertising to Feel Energy Pinch for 15 Years. Advertising Age, July.
1973. Unattributed. Energy Rationing May Limit Ads. New York Times, Nov. 15.
1973. Unattributed. Managing in a Shortage Economy. Business Week, Nov. 10.
1973. Unattributed. New Markets Open with Energy Crisis. Industrial Marketing, Sept.
1974. Elliott, John Jr. The Advertising Business in an Upset Econcomy. Speech delivered at William D. Witter, Inc. Second Annual Consumer Conference, Jan. 30.
1974. Meyer, Edward H. Advertising: New Role in Unabundant Economy. Grey Matter, Feb.
1974. Sawyer, Howard G. Lack of Shortage Ads Likely Means Industry Doesn't See Advertising As Communications Tool. Industrial Marketing, Feb.
1974. Sawyer, Howard G. Up-Coming Era of Opportunity Open to Aggressive Advertisers. Industrial Marketing, Jan.
1974. Unattributed. Advertising in a Period of Shortage Should Help Markets Solve Problems. Industrial Marketing, Feb.
1975. Colarossi, Benjamin, and Baar, James A., Ten Ways to Help Your Company Boost Inflation and Recession. Advertising Age, Mar. 17.
1975. Lamson, John. It Pays to Advertise--Especially During a Period of Recession. Media Decisions, May.
1975. Lazarus, George. It Really Pays to Advertise in Slump. Chicago Tribune, Mar. 5.
1975. Mathews, Carol. No Recession--Ad-Wise. New York Post, May 13.
1975. O'Dwyer, James. The Atmosphere for Advertising in a No-Growth Economy. Madison Avenue Magazine, Apr.
1975. Richmond, Eugene L. Advertising During a Period of Chaotic Uncertainty. Presented at the A.N.A. Advertising Financial Management Workshop, May 18-21.
1975. Spielvogel, Carl. The Opportunity for Business in a Recession Economy. Speech delivered to Los Angeles Ad Club, Jan. 22.
1975. Unattributed. 12 Simple Truths About Selling in a Recession. McGraw Hill Publications.
Undated. Unattributed. 15 Reasons to Continue Advertising When You're Backordered. American Business Press, Inc.